Good Morning Church!
Emmanuel!
(God With Us - Matthew 1:23)
My names are Ochomma Uche.
I am from Imo State, Nigeria.
There are two parts of my testimony.
The first part is confessional.
I belonged to a church, with a group of people who condemned the man of God, who preached against him,
who called him names not only in our congregation but also to members of other churches.
I belonged to one of the foremost ministries in Nigeria.
We had a name for him.
It is very sad to say it but I say it for the glory of God.
They used to call him "tuberculosis".
If you belonged to that church and you are here now - shout "Hallelujah!".
I know some of them are here.
Praise God!
I used to be a pastor and later a member of this church, that I told you about.
We went about vilifying the man of God, speaking evil about him, calling him all sorts of names,
calling him "antychrist" himself.
While we were doing this, it occurred to me that this man that I speak against, that I judge -
I have never heard his word.
I never...
I could not recall any of his word that would be offensive.
So I decided to say, "No. I will look to the scriptures."
My spirit referred me to Acts 17:11.
What makes a man noble is his ability to listen to a message and compare it with scriptures,
besides the miracles.
Because behind any miracle there must be a Word.
So, this drove me to watching Emmanuel TV just to hear the man of God.
When I started listening to the Emmanuel TV, my family was upset with me
because you couldn't watch Emmanuel TV in my place.
Even now, some of my acquaintances who are pastors, evangelists -
as soon as I switch the Emmanuel TV on, they all leave.
Praise God!
I'm sorry sir, before going further - you mentioned you were a pastor in this ministry and you had been involved
in saying many negative things concerning the ministry here - The SCOAN.
Could you just explain a little bit more; for example the kind of prayers that you were offering in that period
and the kind of things that you were saying at that time?
Well, you can imagine what you would say against the man, whose words you never heard.
Because it was a general opinion of our GO, that was the standing order and we believed him.
So, we took him as the antichrist himself - certain incarnate,
who was working miracles with powers that were not of God.
I am talking of Prophet T.B. Joshua - yes.
I was moved to listen to this man, to hear his words, to search the scriptures, to find out if what he is saying
is in accordance with the scriptures.
I started watching Emmanuel TV.
To my greatest surprise, all his teachings, all the words he taught, in their simplicity, they were all
in accordance with the scriptures.
Mr Ochoma Uche
Confession/Deliverance Testimony
It becomes...
His teaching are even more clear.
I began to see the Prophet in a different light.
I began to feel that perhaps I have been condemning an innocent man.
I've been speaking evil against an innocent man.
I felt in my bedroom and I confessed and said, "God, forgive me".
I remember that day.
I confessed, I said, "God, forgive me".
My interest grew to the point that I decided that I would pay a visit to The SCOAN.
You can imagine; I belong to a church where I preach against the man of God - Prophet T.B. Joshua - yes.
At the same time I was involved in "secret sins".
I drank, I smoked, I womanised - you can imagine that...
How a man with this things in his life can condemn a man of God?
I did it.
All this happened in my life for the glory of God.
The truth is: if you are a Christian of any value, none of things I mentioned would ever make you to stand firmly
in the presence of God.
Never!
I know that...
Yes, I was in the ministry, I was teaching and preaching but right inside of me I knew that all this was "in vain".
I tried to hide my sins in many ways.
I would travel 200 kilometres, away from the town, in order to go and indulge myself.
I would out go at night to very dark places in order to smoke.
I would drink secretly in places you would never imagine, because I wouldn't want my parents
my siblings, members of my church to know that I do such deeds.
I am a brethren.
I have fought against these things for very long time.
I have prayed, I have fasted...
I remember that I fasted for 7 days that the Lord should remove this torment from me.
2-3 days after the fasting I went back to it.
I knew that it was a very big problem.
You said sir that you were hiding these acts.
Sometimes you would have to travel a long way to indulge yourself.
Just explain, when you travelled long distances, what would you find yourself doing, even as a pastor.
Of course, I travelled out in order to hide my sins.
I travelled out so no eyes would see me doing these sins, that people who know me would not
recognize me as a person doing such things.
That was why I had to hide.
Yes, sleeping with women, prostitutes, drinking...
I did such things, I did - yes.
It was very heavy on my spirit, because I know that no person who does such things
will ever inherit the kingdom.
It is very clear to me.
I decided to visit Emmanuel TV after seeing wonders here.
Initially, I did not pay attention to miracles.
I was after the Word, because we are redeemed by the Word, through the Word.
When I listened to the Word, I found the Word correct - then I had the strength to come here.
Brethren, when I came here for the first time nobody touched me - I just went through the service on Sunday.
I went home.
As I left here brethren, without being touched by the man of God, without being prophesied to,
the spirits of drinking, smoking and womanising left me automatically.
Mr Ochoma Uche
Confession/DeliveranceTestimony
It became a personal sign to me that there is God in this place.
Emmanuel!
[God with us.]
Brethren, these are the things we did against T.B. Joshua.
I am praying that he forgives me.
I confess publicly.
I know he is hearing my voice.
Let him forgive me for what I have done against him.
I come to what happened here yesterday.
Yesterday, as the man of God was preaching, I was feeling terribly bad inside of me.
It was like sitting on thousand of pins.
My spine, my waist, my belly were hot.
I was feeling hot inside - extreme discomfort.
I was in so much pain that I thought that dying would be better for me then to live with such pains in my body.
When this was going through my body, I remembered his words,
"All this things have come to take away your joy. Refuse it!"
I said, "No, it will not take away my joy. If you are dead you will not take away my life".
I resisted.
This thing came higher and higher to the point where my eyes went black.
I thought I was going to fall down.
What I know, what I had in my ear...
"This is the storm before the calm".
From that point the pain started to recede.
I heard the man of God saying, "In your pains - walk!"
That was what I remembered him saying.
I stood up and started moving my limbs.
To the glory of God - the pain started to recede.
Now, I am very fit, strong, sound.
There are no pains any more in my body.
Amen. Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
Brother is just sharing the instant testimony of what happened yesterday during the mass prayer
concerning the very severe pains he was having.
We want to hear from you again brother; since you first stepped your feet in The SCOAN, you mean to say
that you stopped all the acts of smoking, drinking, womanising, all of that came to an end in the moment
you stepped your feet in here?
That's correct.
They stopped, the urge, you know...
Whatever you do starts from the urge.
It is like a thirst.
Once that emptiness is created in you, you go after it.
Once that emptiness, urge is not there, you cannot commit an act.
The urge, spirit of drinking, womanising, smoking - all of them left me.
Praise God!
Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ one more time.
We thank God that our brother is here in our midst to share this testimony.
We believe there are many valuable lessons that we have learnt from the statements he has made here.
What is your word of advice to our viewers all over the world; especially those who has engaged in such
things in the past, including the acts of blasphemy against the servant of God,
such as Prophet T.B. Joshua?
What would you advise to them based on your own life experience?
My advice to you is: do not allow the opinion of people around you
to steer you away from knowing the truth for yourself.
Do not allow the public opinion to steer you into coming to the partnership with the public.
Before you judge a man, hear him.
Before you find yourself offending somebody, take some time and find out the truth about the person.
What is the point for you to kill a man and later to find out that the man was innocent?
How would you feel?
How would you feel stabbing a man with a sword assuming that he had wounded or killed your brother,
only to find out that the man was innocent?
How would you feel?
That was how I felt.
I wouldn't want anyone to feel like that.
So brethren, my advice is to find our the truth for yourself
and God will bear witness to the man of God.
Praise God.
Amen. Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ.
We can see that as our brother said, the man he that initially condemned, spoke against, used all kinds of
negative words against, ended up being the very same person whom God used to deliver him
from that spirit of womanising, alcohol, and smoking.
We give glory to God that he is here right now.
Just a final word of advice brother - you said that as a pastor you were engaged is such acts.
What do you want to advise people who are still struggling with such addictions,
as someone that passed through that and came out through the deliverance
you received by stepping your feet in here?
What is your advice to such people?
My advice is this: I have tried all my personal strength and I failed.
I have gone through many deliverances; to no avail.
The problem with any sin or addiction is spiritual.
What we need is an intervention of God into this matter.
And the place that I have found, where one can be truly delivered is The SCOAN.
If you cannot find a deliverance elsewhere, let this place be your last bus stop.
Amen. Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ.
Remember, we heard what our brother said.
He said he had just stepped his feet in here.
He wasn't actually prayed for, he didn't receive a prophecy, he didn't even receive ministration with
the morning water.
Just by stepping his feet into the Arena of Liberty that urge left him.
We know that as you are here today in the Arena of Liberty, as you have stepped your feet in here today
for those of us present here - your lives will never remain the same, in Jesus' mighty name.
Brother, we thank God for your life.
We pray that God will you the grace to continue, to make His Word the standard for your life,
and we know that the best is yet to come, in Jesus' name.
Amen.